Guide to the Internation Brotherhood of Teamsters Central Conference of Teamsters records, 1958-1994 IBT0007
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Central Conference of Teamsters records
1954-2001
1982-1994
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
International Brotherhood of Teamsters
IBT0007
9 Linear Feet
This collection contains correspondence, meeting minutes, calendars, legal documents, personnel files, financial records, programs, brochures, and reports. The material dates from 1957-95.
Arrangement
Organized into 6 series: Administrative Files, Policy Committee Meetings and Agendas, Financial Records, Legal Files, Jurisdiction Disputes, and Area Conference Dissolution.
Biographical / Historical
Within the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, between 1937 and 1995, members of the union met and exchanged ideas on a regional basis. These regional organizations were called Area Conferences. In the U.S. there were four Area Conferences: the Western Conference of Teamsters formed in 1937, the Southern Conference of Teamsters formed in 1944, the Central States Conference of Teamsters formed in 1953, and the Eastern Conference of Teamsters also formed in 1953. Canadian Teamsters had their own Canadian Conference of Teamsters, known today as Teamsters Canada. Area Conferences met annually to discuss general issues facing the IBT and to hold discussion more directly relevant to IBT Trade Divisions: contract negotiations, organizing campaigns, workplace disputes, etc.. For example, when the Central States Conference met, after the general sessions, delegates would meet based on the trades they represented: the brewery and soft drink delegates coming together, cannery delegates coming together, dairy delegates coming together, etc.. In this way, the IBT was strengthened in terms of both national and regional coordination of efforts. The Area Conferences came under criticism during the General Presidency of Ron Carey. Making the argument that they were redundant and wasteful, Carey disbanded them in 1995.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence, meeting minutes, calendars, legal documents, personnel files, financial records, programs, brochures, and reports. The material dates from 1957-95. These are the records of the Central Conference of Teamsters, a regional governance body in the structure of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters. The scope of the materials runs from its inception until its dissolution in 1994, the bulk of which are legal and administrative files from the 1970's and 1980's, as well as the controversy regarding the revocation of the charters of the Area Conferences in 1994.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, January 4, 2012 [2012.002].
Conferences; Labor; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor and laboring classes; Labor unions; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America; International Brotherhood of Teamsters
- Administrative Files, 1954-2001; Series 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the administrative files of the Central Conference of Teamsters from 1990-1994 and includes correspondence, agendas, divisional reports, charters, bylaws, and other files pertaining to the everyday operation of the Central Conference.
  - 1991 International Brotherhood of Teamsters Constitution, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1994 Central Conference of Teamsters Convention, Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Automobile Transporters Division, 1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bylaws Revisions, 1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - CCT Officer's Report, 11-14 October 1971; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - CCT Officer's Report, 3-5 December 1973; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - CCT Officer's Report, 1975; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - CCT Officer's Report, 18-20 February 1979; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - CCT Officer's Report, 8-13 February 1987; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Central Conference Area Reports, 1959-1973; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Central Conference Bylaws, 1990; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Central Conference of Teamsters 10th Meeting - Chairman's Report, 1966; Series 1 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Central Conference of Teamsters 13th Meeting - Chairman's Report (2 Copies), 11 October - 14 October, 1971; Series 1 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Central States General Correspondence, 1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Central States Personnel, 1992-1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chairman's Annual Report CCT, 25-26 April 1954; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Chairman's Annual Report CCT, 16 April 1955; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Chairman's Annual Report CCT, 10-11 May 1956; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Chairman's Annual Report CCT, 1957; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Chairman's Annual Report CCT, 1958; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Chairman's Annual Report CCT, 1959; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Chairman's Annual Report CCT, 1961; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Chairman's Annual Report CCT, 1963; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Chairman's Annual Report CCT, 1966; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Chairman's Annual Report CCT, 1967; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Director, National Freight Division, 1994; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Directory - Central Conference, April 1975; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Divisional Reports, 1991-1993; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Divisional Reports, 1992-1994; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Emergency Assessment, 1994; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Hazardous Waste Program, 1994; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Human Rights Commission, 1994; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Illinois Commerce Commission, 1994; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Industrial Engineering, 1994; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters National Grievance Committee, 1992-1993; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters Trusteeship Hearing (regarding Local 916) [1/2], 1994; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters Trusteeship Hearing (regarding Local 916) [2/2], 1994; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Leave Policies, 1988; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Legislative (IBT), 1994-1995; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Locals Administrative Files, 1991-1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1994-1995; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - New Charters, Revised Charters, and Mergers, 1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Notes For Trade Union Organizers, 1955; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Organizing, 1994; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Region Meeting, 22-25 April 2001; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Resolutions, 1994; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Safety and Health, 1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Survey of White collar Workers, December 1976; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Central Conference of Teamsters, Survey of Agreements, June 1976; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Central Conference of Teamsters, Survey of Agreements, July 1977; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Central Conference of Teamsters, Survey of White Collar Workers, December 1976; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Central Conference of Teamsters, Survey of White Collar Workers 1 of 2, March 1979; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Central Conference of Teamsters, Survey of White Collar Workers 2 of 2, March 1979; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Teamster Education/Training and Development Department Airline Industry Grievance Handling, Undated; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Teamster Education/Training and Development Department Railway Labor Act Grievance Process, Undated; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Teamster Education/Training and Development Department Railway Labor Act Grievance Process, Undated; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Teamster Training and Development Department Records, Mock Contract, Undated; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Teamster Education/Training and Development Department Railway Labor Act Mediation Process, 1999; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Teamster Training and Development Department Records, Steward Information Manual, Undated; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Policy Committee Meetings and Agendas, 1983-1993; Series 2
  Arranged chronologically.
  This series contains the Minutes and Agendas of the Central Conference of Teamsters Policy Committee, the central administrative authority of the Conference. The materials in this series range from 1983-1993.
  - Central Conference of Teamsters 21st Meeting Report of Officers, February 8-13, 1987; Series 2 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Policy Committee Agendas and Minutes, 1983-1984; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Policy Committee Agendas and Minutes, 1985-1987; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Policy Committee Agendas and Minutes, 1988-1989; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Policy Committee Agendas and Minutes, 1989; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Policy Committee Agendas and Minutes, 1989-1990; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Policy Committee Agendas and Minutes, 1992-1993; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Teamster Training and Development Department Records, Local Union 429 Stewards Seminar Manual, April 22, 2006; Series 2 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Teamster Training and Development Department Records, Local Union 878 Stewards Seminar Manual, September 9, 2006; Series 2 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Teamster Training and Development Department Records, Local Union 991 Stewards Seminar Manual, February 3, 2007; Series 2 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Teamster Training and Development Department Records, Local Union 429 Stewards Seminar Manual, March 24, 2007; Series 2 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Financial Records, 1991-1996; Series 3
  This series contains all financial materials related to the Central Conference of Teamsters, including receipts, bills, financial statements, bank statements, and tax documentation. The materials in this series range in date from 1991 to 1995.
  - Banquet Foods Pensions [1/2], 1994; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Banquet Foods Pensions [2/2], 1994; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - CCT CSS Benefit Plans A and C, 1979; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - CCT CSS Pension Plan Info, 1980; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Certificate of Deposit Activity, 1994; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Employer Tax Documentation, 1994; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Estimated Costs for All Grievance Committees, 1994; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - First Colonial Bank, 1994-1995; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Human Resources Grant, 1994; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Insurance, 1994; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Legal Bills, 1993; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Leahy and Associates Insurance, 1995; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Reviewed Financial Statements Ending Sept 30, 1992, Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Sale of Cars, 1994; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Schedule of Federal Financial Assistance, 1991-1992; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Strike Fund, 1994; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Unaudited Financial Statements, 1991-1993; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1992 Audited Financial Statements, Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Legal Files, 1973-1995; Series 4
  This series includes legal files collected by the Central Conference of Teamsters from 1973-1995, including cases against the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, cases involving Local Unions, and those involving labor disputes with private organizations.
  - ABF/Carolina Merger, 1995; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Conference Dissolution Lawsuit, 30 March 1994; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Discrimination Litigation, 1994; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - FRT Litigation: CRST, Inc. Case No: 80L18877, 1978-1981; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - FRT Litigation: Cummings v. Tucker Freight, 1982; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - FRT Litigation: John Trail et al v. IBT, Michigan Local Unions, and Motor Carrier Association of Michigan, 1973; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - FRT Litigation: Zeiner v. Eastern Express, 1976-1977; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - FRT Litigation: Wilson Freight Forwarding Co., 1978; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Litigation: Bortell, Chafee, et al v. CRST Inc, Local 710, IBT, 1975; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Litigation: Central Cartage / Central Transport, 1994; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Litigation: Dave Spencer, et al v. IBT, et al; Case No: 82-1441, 1982; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Litigation: Gayness v. IBT, et al; Case No: C-2-81-1009, 1982; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Litigation: Gayness, et al v. IBT, Local 413, Commercial Lovelace, 1983; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Litigation: Greg Roberson v. Allied Delivery System, IBT; Case No: C81-1982, 1981-1983; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Litigation: Illinois Conference of Teamsters v. Illinois Tank Truck Carriers Association, Case No: 81-3022, 1981; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Litigation: Interstate Truck Service; NLRB Case Nos: 6-CA-12602, 6-CA-12691, 1982; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Litigation: Lee Way Freight System & Local 332, 1983; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Litigation: Local #30 v. Helms Express, Inc., 1979; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Litigation: Local 364 v. Oil Express, Inc., Pacer Oil Company, B&B leading Corporation, 1982; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Litigation: Lovelace Trucking and Local Union #413, 1977; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Litigation: Maxwell Company v. Central Conference of Teamsters and Local 114; Case Nos: 6-CA-12602, 6-CA-12691, 1982; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Litigation: Michigan Teamsters v. Bufalino, et al; Case No: 82-74597, 1982; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Litigation: Mid-American Lines, Inc. Chapter 11; Case No:82-00639-3-11, 1982; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Litigation: McBride's Express, Inc. v. IBT, et al; Case No: 82-1095-C, 1982; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Litigation: National Homes; Case Nos: 14-CA-12589, 14-CA-13111, 14-CA-13112, 14-CA-13113, 1979; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Litigation: Roadway Workers, Inc. vs. Roadway Express, Inc; Case No: C82-619, 1981-1982; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Litigation: Ruan v. IBT, et al; Case No: 79-152-2, 1979; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Litigation: Ruan Transit Corp. v. IBT, Case No: C-49-3, 1979; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Litigation: Ruan v. IBT, et al; Case No: C-79-34-1, 1979; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Litigation: Ruan v. IBT, et al; Case No: C-3-79-49, 1979; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Litigation: Schneider Transport, Allan Enochs v. Schneider, et al; Case No: 82-2235-C, 1983; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Litigation: Spector Freight Systems et al; Case No: 79-C-277 [1/2], 1979; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Litigation: Spector Freight Systems et al; Case No: 79-C-277 [2/2], 1979; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Litigation: Red Ball Truck and Leasing; Case No: 82-03728-W, 1982; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Litigation: Roadway Express, et. al. Case No: C80-2338, 1980-1984; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Litigation: Schwerman Trucking Company; NLRB Case No: 33-CA-5319, 1981; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Litigation: Three-Star Construction Company; Case No: BK 81-40281, 1981; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Litigation: TIME-DC, Inc.; Case No: 16-CA-10543, 1983; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Litigation: Trout Air Freight; Case No: 33-CB-1834, 1982; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Litigation: Transport Service Co. v. Central Conference of Teamsters, Local 279; Case No: 82C-1963, 1982; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Litigation:Wattenbarger v. Beatrice Foods, Local 460, 1982; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Nancy DeLong Information [1/2], 1994-1995; Series 4 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Nancy DeLong Information [2/2], 1994-1995; Series 4 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Nancy DeLong suit vs. IBT [1/2], 1994-1996; Series 4 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Nancy DeLong suit vs. IBT [2/2], 1994-1996; Series 4 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - National Steel Carriers Association et al; NLRB Case: 8-CA-15927, 1984-1986; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - NLRB Case 30-CA-10339, 1989-1991; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - NLRB Charge Against Employer GMW, 1983; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - NLRB Litigation: Maislin Transport Limited; Case No: 5-CA-14430, 1983; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - NLRB Litigation: FX Coughlin Co; Case No: 7-CA-22885, 1984; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - M&H Transport, Domino Cartage, Local 299, 1984; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Maureen Dugan, 1994; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Mine Workers [1/2], 1991-1992; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Mine Workers [2/2], 1991-1992; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Previant, Goldberg, Uelmen, et. al., 1994; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Robert E. Knox, 1994-1995; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Jurisdiction Disputes, 1973-1993; Series 5
  This series includes the collected files of the Central Conference of Teamsters concerning jurisdictional disputes between Local Unions under the aegis of the Central Conference, from 1973-1994.
  - Central Conference Of Teamsters Frieght Distributions - Dispute Resolutions, 8-10 March 1982; Series 5 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Jurisdiction Dispute: Locals 124 and 299 [1/4], 1973-1981; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Jurisdiction Dispute: Locals 124 and 299 [2/4], 1977-1982; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Jurisdiction Dispute: Locals 124 and 299 [3/4], 1981; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Jurisdiction Dispute: Locals 124 and 299 [4/4], 1981; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Jurisdiction Dispute: Locals 26, 50, 144, 215, 279, 298, 347, 364, 371, 414, 525, 543, 627, 710, 722, 916, 1990-1991; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Jurisdiction Dispute: Locals 579 and 744, 1991; Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Jurisdiction Dispute: Locals 215 and 783 [1/2], 1992-1993; Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Jurisdiction Dispute: Locals 215 and 783 [2/2], 1992-1993; Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Jurisdiction Dispute: Locals 124 and 710, 1992; Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Jurisdiction Dispute: Locals 142 and 505, 1992; Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Jurisdiction Dispute: Locals 135 and 142 [1/2], 1993; Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Jurisdiction Dispute: Locals 135 and 142 [2/2], 1993; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Jurisdiction Dispute: Locals 673 and 722, 1994; Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Jurisdiction Disputes, 1993; Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Area Conference Dissolution, 1994-1996; Series 6
  This series includes material leading up to and concerning the revocation of the Area Conference Charters and subsequent dissolution of the Area Conferences within the larger International Brotherhood of Teamsters, from 1992-1994. By the end of 1995, the Central Conference of Teamsters ceased to exist and local unions which were previously a part of the Central Conference fall under the authority of Joint Councils.
  - Central Conference Personnel Termination Letters, 1994-1996; Series 6 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence between Carey and Hogan [1/2], 1994; Series 6 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence between Carey and Hogan [2/2], 1994; Series 6 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters Dues Increase and Spec. Convention [1/5], 1994; Series 6 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters Dues Increase and Spec. Convention [2/5], 1994; Series 6 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters Dues Increase and Spec. Convention [3/5], 1994; Series 6 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters Dues Increase and Spec. Convention [4/5], 1994; Series 6 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters Dues Increase and Spec. Convention [5/5], 1994; Series 6 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Letters of Support for the Central Conference of Teamsters [1/3], 1994; Series 6 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Letters of Support for the Central Conference of Teamsters [2/3], 1994; Series 6 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Letters of Support for the Central Conference of Teamsters [3/3], 1994; Series 6 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Per Capita Tax Increase, 1991-1993; Series 6 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Revocation of Central Conference of Teamsters Charter [1/3], 1994; Series 6 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Revocation of Central Conference of Teamsters Charter [2/3], 1994; Series 6 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Revocation of Central Conference of Teamsters Charter [3/3], 1994; Series 6 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - US Area Conferences Revocation Hearing [1/2], 1994; Series 6 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - US Area Conferences Revocation Hearing [2/2], 1994; Series 6 (Box 7, Folder 5)